A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of the President, Office Files of McGeorge Bundy FA617
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Subject Files, 1969-1976; bulk; II; 13 Box(es)
  - Children's Television, 1972 - 1975 (Box 11, Folder 129)
  - Chinese Journalists Luncheon, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 130)
  - Columbia University, 1966 - 1968 (Box 11, Folder 131-132)
  - Columbus Day Committee, 1974 - 1975 (Box 11, Folder 133)
  - Commission on Private Philanthropy and Public Needs (Box 11, Folder -)
    SEE: Filer Commission
  - Communications Media Council, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 134)
  - Comptroller, Role of the, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 135)
  - Congress for Cultural Freedom, 1966 - 1967 (Box 11, Folder 136)
  - Co-ordinating Committee on Women's Programs, 1971 - 1978 (Box 11, Folder 137)
  - Council on Foundations, 1972 - 1975 (Box 11, Folder 138)
  - Council on Foundations and Foundation Center Merger, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 139)
  - Council on Library Resources, 1973 - 1974 (Box 11, Folder 140)
  - Decentralization - Meetings - Panel Meetings, 1967 August 24 (Box 11, Folder 141)
  - Decentralization - Meetings - Panel Meetings, 1967 August 3 (Box 11, Folder 142)
  - Decentralization - Meetings - Panel Meetings, 1967 July 20 (Box 11, Folder 143)
  - Decentralization - Meetings - Panel Meetings, 1967 July 7 (Box 12, Folder 144)
  - Decentralization - Meetings - Panel Meetings, 1967 June 13 (Box 12, Folder 145)
  - Decentralization - Meetings - Panel Meetings, 1967 May 11 (Box 12, Folder 146)
  - Decentralization - Meetings - Outside Meetings, 1967 October 3 (Box 12, Folder 147)
  - Decentralization - Panel Report - Final Report: Reconnection for Learning, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 148)
  - Decentralization - Panel Report - Report Drafts (Box 12, Folder 149-150)
  - Decentralization - Panel Report - Draft Letter of Transmittal, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 151)
  - Decentralization - Panel Report - Status Reports, 1967 July 26, June 12 (Box 12, Folder 152)
  - Decentralization - Panel Report - Staff Background Papers (Box 12, Folder 153)
  - Decentralization - Consultants' Reports - CONSAD "Feasibility of Devising New School Districts" (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - Decentralization - Consultants' Reports - MARC "An Intensive Program for the Attainment..." (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - Decentralization - Consultants' Reports - NYU "A Report on the Recruitment, Selection, ..." (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - Decentralization - Consultants' Reports - Quayle "A Cursory Study of White Middle-Class..." (Box 12, Folder 157)
  - Decentralization - Consultants' Reports - Price Waterhouse "New York City Schools Decentralization" (Box 13, Folder 158)
  - Decentralization - Consultants' Reports - Simon "Draft Plan of Mayor's Advisory Panel on..." (Box 13, Folder 159)
  - Decentralization - Consultants' Reports - Stanford Research Institute "Budget Decentralization, Comments on the Management Implications of..." (Box 13, Folder 160)
  - Decentralization - Consultants' Reports - Thabit "A Report on School Districting to the Task Force..." (Box 13, Folder 161)
  - Decentralization - Correspondence, n.d. - 1967 (Box 13, Folder 162-164)
  - Decentralization - Legislation (Box 13, Folder 165)
  - Dependent Organizations, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 166)
  - Developing Countries, 1971 - 1972 (Box 13, Folder 167)
  - Drug Abuse, 1970 - 1973 (Box 13, Folder 168)
  - Encounter, NYT, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Endowment Management, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Energy Policy Project, 1972 - 1977 (Box 13, Folder 171-172)
  - Energy Policy Project - Tavoulareas, 1974 - 1975 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - Environmental Institute, 1969 - 1973 (Box 14, Folder 174)
  - European and North American Foundations Meeting (Canceled), 1975 (Box 14, Folder 175)
  - External Affirmative Action, 1972 - 1977 (Box 14, Folder 176)
  - Faisal Foundation, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 177)
  - Filer Commission, 1974 - 1975 (Box 14, Folder 178)
  - F.O.R.D. [Families Opposed to Revolutionary Donations], 1970 (Box 14, Folder 179)
  - Ford Foundation and Women, 1970 - 1973 (Box 14, Folder 180)
  - Ford Foundation Convocation, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 181)
  - Ford Foundation Program and Policy, 1970 January (Box 14, Folder 182)
  - Ford Foundation Self Study, 1971 - 1972 (Box 14, Folder 183)
  - Ford Foundation Task Forces, 1972 - 1974 (Box 14, Folder 184)
  - Ford II, Henry - Resignation, 1977 January (Box 15, Folder 185)
  - Ford Motor Co., complaints about FF activities, 1966 - 1967 (Box 15, Folder 186)
  - Foundation Center, 1969 - 1973 (Box 15, Folder 187)
  - Foundations and Government, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 188)
  - Fund for the City of New York, 1967 - 1968 (Box 15, Folder 189)
  - Future of American Society, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 190)
    SEE ALSO: American Values Meeting
  - Future Program Planning Project, 1975 - 1976 (Box 15, Folder 191)
  - Gardner, John W., 1967 - 1977 (Box 15, Folder 192)
  - Graduate Education, 1966 - 1967 (Box 15, Folder 193)
  - Great Books, 1968 - 1971 (Box 15, Folder 194)
  - Government and Higher Education Research SEE: Seven Springs Group (Box 15, Folder -)
  - Helsinki Watch, 1978 - 1979 (Box 15, Folder 195)
  - Human Rights, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 196)
  - Industrialized Societies, 1966 - 1968 (Box 16, Folder 197-199)
  - Instructional Television, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 200)
  - International Center for Law and Development, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 201)
  - International Fellows Program, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 202)
  - Investment Policies, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 203)
  - Japan Foundation, 1972 - 1976 (Box 16, Folder 204)
  - Japan Center for International Exchange, 1971 - 1972 (Box 16, Folder 205)
  - Japanese-American Assembly, 1972 - 1976 (Box 16, Folder 206)
  - Lawyers Committee for Civil Rights, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 207)
  - Library of Congress, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 208)
  - Longstreth, Bevis, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 209)
  - Mayor's Advisory Panel on the Decentralization of New York City Schools (Box 16, Folder -)
    SEE: Decentralization
  - Middle East Conference, 1975 - 1976 (Box 16, Folder 210)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 211)
  - National Advisory Commission on Civil Disturbances, 1967 - 1968 (Box 16, Folder 212)
  - National Urban League, 1969 - 1974 (Box 16, Folder 213)
  - Negro Education, 1965 - 1967 (Box 17, Folder 214)
  - New York Public Library, 1969 - 1974 (Box 17, Folder 215)
  - Nielsen [, Waldermar] Interview, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 216)
  - Noll, Roger, 1968 - 1971 (Box 17, Folder 217)
  - Nuclear Analysis Program, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 218)
  - Nuclear Energy Policy Study Group, 1975 - 1977 (Box 17, Folder 219)
  - Outside Affiliations, 1972 - 1975 (Box 17, Folder 220)
  - Patman, Rep. Wright, 1967 - 1968 (Box 17, Folder 221)
  - PAYE [Pay As You Earn], 1968 - 1971 (Box 17, Folder 222)
  - Peterson Commission on Foundations, 1969 - 1970 (Box 17, Folder 223)
  - Police Foundation, 1970 - 1972 (Box 17, Folder 224)
  - Public Broadcasting Laboratory, 1967 - 1968 (Box 17, Folder 225)
  - Public Interest Law, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 226)
  - Public Opinion, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 227)
  - Public Policy, 1971 - 1978 (Box 18, Folder 228)
  - Public Television, 1970 - 1976 (Box 18, Folder 229)
  - Racial Policy Issues, Ad hoc Committee on, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 230)
  - Resources for the Future, 1974, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 231)
  - Resources for the Future/Brookings Merger, 1977 - 1978 (Box 18, Folder 232)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, Comments on Annual Report, 1973 September - October (Box 18, Folder 233)
  - Russian Research Center, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 234)
  - Senate Finance Committee, 1969 - 1970 (Box 18, Folder 235-236)
  - Senate Finance Committee - Reduction of 4% Tax, 1973 - 1978 (Box 18, Folder 237)
  - Senate Subcommittee on Domestic Finance. Committee on Banking and Finance, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 238)
  - Seven Springs Group, 1977 - 1978 (Box 18, Folder 239)
  - Social Responsibility and Investment (Box 18, Folder -)
    SEE: Longstreth, Bevis
  - Tax Reform Act of 1969, 1969 - 1970 (Box 19, Folder 240-241)
  - Tax Reform Act of 1969 - "40 Year" Life (Box 19, Folder 242)
  - Tax Reform Act of 1969 - Related Material, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 243)
  - Tax Reform Act of 1969 - Views on Restrictive Legislations (Box 19, Folder 244)
    Separated Materials
    Removed to Parallel File
  - Tax Reform Act of 1969 - Lauren Williams [Foundation Lawyers], 1969 - 1970 (Box 19, Folder 245)
    SEE ALSO: Peterson Commission, Senate Subcommittee on Domestic Finance, Senate Finance Committee, Ways and Means Committee
  - Television - Correspondence, 1966 - 1969 (Box 19, Folder 246-250)
  - Television - Carnegie Commission on Educational Television, 1965 - 1967 (Box 20, Folder 251)
  - Television - ETV Network Demonstration Broadcast, 1966 - 1967 (Box 20, Folder 252)
  - Television - FCC Filings, 1966 August 1 (Box 20, Folder 253)
  - Television - FCC Filings, 1966 December 12 (Box 20, Folder 254-256)
  - Television - FCC Filings, 1967 April 3 (Box 20, Folder 257)
  - Television - FCC Filings, 1967 September 18 (Box 21, Folder 258)
  - Television - FCC Filings, 1968 October 16 (Box 21, Folder 259)
  - Television - FCC Filings, 1970 December 7 (Box 21, Folder 260)
  - Television - Memoranda, Memoranda 1966 - 1967 (Box 21, Folder 261-264)
  - Television - Press Release, Press Release 1966 August 1 (Box 21, Folder 265)
  - Urban Institute, 1969 - 1974 (Box 21, Folder 266)
  - Vietnam Offenders Study, 1974 - 1977 (Box 22, Folder 267)
  - Ways and Means Committee, 1967 - 1969 (Box 22, Folder 268)
  - White House Conference on Food, Nutrition, and Health, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 269)
  - Wolfson College, 1966, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 270)
- Correspondence and Memoranda to Staff, 1966-1979; bulk; III; 3 Box(es)
  CORRESPONDENCE subseries includes letters from people outside the Foundation: members of Congress, former grantees, job seekers, and other individuals with an interest in the Ford Foundation. Some of these letters are accompanied by Bundy’s response. This subseries also includes a small amount of misfiled correspondence from Foundation staff members. Typical of this subseries is a letter from Professor Nelson W. Polsky ruminating on topics covered in the Foundation-sponsored seminar on American values (this seminar is documented in SERIES II). The subseries MEMORANDA TO STAFF consists of Bundy's announcements to Foundation staff. There are also a few announcements addressed to the Foundation’s executive officers interfiled here. This subseries provides a sketchy chronology of many Foundation activities and events.
  Divided into two subseries: CORRESPONDENCE and MEMORANDA TO STAFF.
  Each subseries is arranged chronologically. Items in the folders of the CORRESPONDENCE subseries are arranged alphabetically by name.
  - Correspondence, 1966 - 1972 (Box 23, Folder 271-283)
  - Correspondence, 1973 - 1979 (Box 24, Folder 284-293)
  - Memoranda, 1966 - 1979 (Box 25, Folder 294-299)
- Trustees Files, 1966-1979; bulk; IV; 3 Box(es)
  Consists of memoranda and some correspondence, agendas, and some "post-board briefings" (outlines of addresses to Foundation staff).
  The TRUSTEE LETTERS contain Mr. Bundy's outgoing correspondence to the Board of Trustees. Most of the "Letters" are transmittal notes. However, some of the correspondence is more substantive. Many of these more-in-depth letters are duplicated elsewhere; for example, a letter dated September 9, 1966, on satellite television, is also filed in the Subject Files. The TRUSTEE MEETINGS subseries contains mailings to the Trustees, meeting agendas, and a small amount of correspondence with individual trustees. Most useful are Howard Dressner's memoranda to Bundy suggesting topics for post-Board briefings to the staff; some of these memoranda are duplicated in Series I. The TRUSTEE MEETINGS subseries does not include Trustee meeting minutes which can be found as part of the Board of Trustees records.
  Divided into two subseries: TRUSTEE LETTERS and TRUSTEE MEETINGS.
  The LETTERS TO TRUSTEES are arranged chronologically. Within each folder the letters are arranged in reverse chronological order.
  The TRUSTEES MEETINGS folders are arranged chronologically by date of the meeting; the material within each folder is arranged in reverse chronological order.
  - Letters to Trustees, 1966 - 1979 (Box 26, Folder 300-308)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1967 September (Box 27, Folder 309)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1970 June (Box 27, Folder 310)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1970 December (Box 27, Folder 311)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1971 March (Box 27, Folder 312)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1971 June (Box 27, Folder 313)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1971 September (Box 27, Folder 314)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1971 December (Box 27, Folder 315)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1972 March (Box 27, Folder 316)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1972 June (Box 27, Folder 317)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1972 September (Box 27, Folder 318)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1972 December (Box 27, Folder 319)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1973 March (Box 27, Folder 320)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1973 June (Box 27, Folder 321)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1973 September (Box 27, Folder 322)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1973 December (Box 27, Folder 323)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1974 March (Box 27, Folder 324)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1974 June (Box 27, Folder 325)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1974 September (Box 27, Folder 326)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1974 December (Box 27, Folder 327)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1975 March (Box 27, Folder 328)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1975 June (Box 27, Folder 329-330)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1975 September (Box 28, Folder 331)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1975 December (Box 28, Folder 332)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1976 March (Box 28, Folder 333)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1976 June (Box 28, Folder 334)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1976 September (Box 28, Folder 335)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1976 December (Box 28, Folder 336)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1977 March (Box 28, Folder 337)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1977 June (Box 28, Folder 338)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1977 September (Box 28, Folder 339)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1977 December (Box 28, Folder 340)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1978 March (Box 28, Folder 341)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1978 June (Box 28, Folder 342)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1978 September (Box 28, Folder 343)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1978 December (Box 28, Folder 344)
  - Trustee Meetings, 1979 March (Box 28, Folder 345)
- Budget Files, 1970-1979; bulk; V; 1 Box(es)
  The budget papers themselves have been removed and transferred to the Ford Foundation archives' collection of Budget Papers. Cross-reference sheets have been inserted to note the original locations of the budget papers.
  The material is in chronological order; within each folder, the material is arranged in reverse chronological order.
  Consists of memoranda related to the preparation of office and division budgets. Budget books and other reports have been transferred to the appropriate collections; cross-reference sheets have been inserted at the original location of each removed item. The budget books contain useful summaries of budget planning including program policy analysis.
  - Budget FY 1970, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 346)
  - Budget FY 1971, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 347)
  - Budget FY 1972, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 348)
  - Budget FY 1973, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 349)
  - Budget FY 1974-75, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 350-351)
  - Budget FY 1975-76, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 352-353)
  - Budget FY 1976-77, 1975 - 1976 (Box 29, Folder 354)
  - Budget FY 1978-79, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 355)
- Trip Files, 1966-1971, 1974-1979; VI; 2 Box(es)
  Series VI consists of trip itineraries, correspondence and memoranda, biographical briefings, an interview transcript, and some photographs.
  Contains information on Mr. Bundy's overseas travel in his capacity as President of the Ford Foundation. Most of the information contained in the files is sketchy; however, there are a few items of particular interest. For example, Folder 360, Asia 1968, includes a transcript of a television interview with Bundy in Karachi, Pakistan; Folder 371, Asia 1974, contains letters from Indians apologizing for their students "misbehaving" (demonstrating) at the India International Centre during Bundy's visit.
  The material is in chronological order by date of trip. Items within each folder are roughly in chronological order.
  - Japan, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 355-356)
  - Japan - photographs, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 357)
  - Europe, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 358)
  - Europe, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 359)
  - Asia, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 360)
  - Middle East, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 361)
  - Nairobi, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 362)
  - Africa (canceled), 1969 (Box 30, Folder 363)
  - West Africa, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 364-365)
  - Latin America, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 366)
  - Scotland, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 367)
  - London - Paris, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 368)
  - Far East, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 369)
  - Far East - photographs, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 370)
  - Asia, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 371)
  - Japan, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 372)
  - Mexico City, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 373)
  - Middle East, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 374-375)
  - Latin America, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 376)
  - Asia, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 377-378)
  - Asia - photographs, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 379)
  - India, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 380)
  - Germany and London, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 381)
- Parallel Files, 1966-1979; VII; 1 Box(es)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Series 7 Parallel Files is restricted from scholarly access.
  These files reflect the arrangements of Series I-VI.
  Consist of documents with personnel-related matters such as salaries, position appointments, recommendations, and evaluations, as well as documents removed out of consideration for an individual's privacy.
  - Operations and Administration
    Restricted from scholarly access.
    - Armsey, James, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 381)
    - Cook, Samuel, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 382)
    - de Janosi, Peter, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 383)
    - Cheit, Earl, 1971 - 1972 (Box 32, Folder 384)
    - Kelly, James, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 385)
    - Lowry, W. McNeil, 1973 - 1974 (Box 32, Folder 386)
    - Kennedy, Roger, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 387)
    - National Affairs/Government & Law, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 388)
    - Pincus, William, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 389)
    - Coleman, John, 1965 - 1967 (Box 32, Folder 390)
    - Harrison, Gordon, 1967 - 1968 (Box 32, Folder 391)
    - Resources and Environment, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 392)
    - International Division, 1966, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 393)
    - Bell, David, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 394)
    - Ward, F. Champion, 1967 - 1970 (Box 32, Folder 395)
    - Silj, Alessandro, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 396)
    - Staples, Eugene, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 397)
    - Middle East & Africa, 1972 - 1973 (Box 32, Folder 398)
    - Edwards, Robert, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 399)
    - Latin America, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 400)
    - India, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 401)
    - Lowenthal, Abraham, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 402)
    - Bowles, Frank, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 403)
    - Borgmann, Carl, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 404)
    - Bohen, Fred, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 405)
    - Smith, Ted, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 406)
    - Cuninggim, Merrimon, 1973 - 1975 (Box 32, Folder 407)
    - Trottenberg, Arthur, 1969 - 1978 (Box 32, Folder 408)
    - Kelly, Eamon, 1976 - 1977 (Box 32, Folder 409)
    - Dressner, Howard, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 410)
    - Kennedy, Roger, 1970 - 1976 (Box 32, Folder 411)
    - Lenagh, Thomas, 1969, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 412)
    - Clemente, Lilia, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 413)
    - Porter, Henry, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 414)
    - Office of Reports, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 415)
  - Subject Files
    Restricted from scholarly access
    - Arms Control, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 416)
    - Atlantic Institute, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 417)
    - Columbia University, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 418)
    - Noll, Roger, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 419)
    - Public Television, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 420)
    - Resources for the Future, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 421)
    - Television, 1966 - 1967 (Box 32, Folder 422)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1969 - 1978 (Box 32, Folder 423)
  - Trustee Meetings
    - Trustee Meeting, 1971 March (Box 32, Folder 424)
    - Trustee Meeting, 1977 November (Box 32, Folder 425)
- Appendix A: Reports
  - n.a. Statement of Initial Witnesses Appearing before the Senate Finance Committee, 1969 September (Report 10879)
  - Advisory Committee on Endowment Management. Managing Educational Endowments, 1968 December (Report 2843)
  - Armsey, James W. Current Programs of Assistance to Predominately Negro Colleges, 1967 (Report 11085)
  - Atwater, Verne S. F.C.C. Television Proposal, 1966 July (Report 10943)
  - Atwater, Verne S. The Foundation's Responsibilities to New York City: Four Alternative Means of Payment, 1968 (Report 11087)
  - Bader, William. [Development of the Paris Office], 1971 (Report 11058)
  - Bader, William. Suggestions Concerning a Foundation Program for Support of Research Projects in the Arms Control Field, 1974 July (Report 3414)
  - Bass, Milton R. I was an Educational TV Dropout, n.d. (Report 10947)
  - Bell, David E. Budget planning paper, FY 1974-75, International Division, 1973 February (Report 9010)
  - Bell, David E. Highlight Observations on the Situation in India and the Foundation's Program There, 1967 December (Report 9078)
  - Bell, David E. Items for the Foundation's "Planning, Exploration, and Evaluation Agenda", 1972 February (Report 2462)
  - Bell, David E. Notes on Asia, October 1973, 1973 December (Report 4560)
  - Bell, David E. Notes on North and West Africa, 1968 August (Report 6253)
  - Bell, David E. The Plight of Foreign Aid. Kenya Meeting of Representatives, 1968 (Report 9175)
  - Bell, David E. Travel Notes, April 11-May 8, 1976 (Report 11069)
  - Bell, David E. Visit to Asia, November 12-December 5, 1974, 1974 December (Report 10962)
  - Bell, David E. Visit to the Middle East, February 23-March 8, 1969 (Report 11071)
  - Bohrson, Ralph G. Public School Desegregation - Proposed Future Plans, 1976 (Report 11084)
  - Booz, Allen & Hamilton. Survey of Administrative Organization, 1964 July (Report 10421)
  - Borgmann, Carl W. Federal Support of Basic Scientific Research in Universities, 1969 (Report 11043)
  - Borgmann, Carl W. Observations on Foundation Activities in Science and Technology in Asia, 1968 (Report 11042)
  - Borgmann, Carl W. The Private Institutions of Higher Education Emphasizing Science and Technology, 1966 June (Report 10953)
  - Bowles, Frank. [Educational Opportunities for Negroes], 1966 July (Report 10251)
  - Bowles, Frank. Planning for Foundation Activities in Europe, 1968 January (Report 10257)
  - Bowles, Frank. Travel Diary for Puerto Rico Trip -- March 13-16, 1967, 1967 March (Report 10268)
  - Bowles, Frank. Trip Diary - American Samoa -- From October 4, 1966 to October 12, 1966, 1966 October (Report 10269)
  - Bresnan, John. Dr. Soedjatmoko and the Political Situation in Indonesia, 1974 (Report 11054)
  - Brooks, Richard. Draft Summary of an Assessment of the Foundation's Grant to the National Council of Crime & Delinquency (N.C.C.D.), 1969 June (Report 2259)
  - Bryant, James W. Review of Program Aims and Objectives, 1970 (Report 11083)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Claims on General Reserve, 1978 November (Report 4643)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Discussion in the Soviet Union and Western Europe on the Idea of a Center for the Study of Common Problems in Advanced Societies, 1967 September (Report 10994)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. The Ford Foundation Press Conference, 1966 August (Report 10919)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Foundation Policies Related to the U.S. Balance of Payments, 1968 April (Report 8964)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Guidelines for Management of Special Fund for Michigan, 1973 September (Report 10924)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Interim Report Concerning "Self-Study" Process, 1971 September (Report 5599)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Memorandum for the Board of Trustees re: Henry Ford Hospital, 1973 March (Report 10927)